In this video, I'll be showing you how to deploy a Microsoft Store app using Microsoft Intune.
So, let's say you want to deploy the remote desktop tool using Microsoft Intune.
I'm going to show you how to do that in this video.
But, you know, sometimes if I'm working for a company and in that company, the Microsoft Store
has been blocked.
So, definitely, the Microsoft Store apps you want to deploy using Microsoft Intune and
this app come with different ways.
So, let me show you how to deploy this app.
So, for example, if I go to my apps in point.maxoff.com and I go to all apps and I click Add.
Here you can see we can actually just select App Type and then we're going to actually
just go for the Microsoft Store app.
You can see all the store app we have, the Android Store app, the iOS, we're actually interested
in the Microsoft Store app.
You can see we have the legacy or the new.
So, I'm going to go for the new because it's actually new to endpoints manager.
So, let's just click that and then we're going to click Select.
So right now, you know, previously, if you want to deploy a Store app, you need to go
to a link and then take the link of that app and then paste it on in Intune.
But now, you don't need to acknowledge just set the Microsoft Store app and then what you
need to do, I'm going to acknowledge just enter the remote desktop and then hit enter.
You can see it's going to give me the Microsoft Store, remote desktop and some other remote
desktop.
So, let me just select Microsoft, remote desktop and then click Select.
And automatically, you can see all the required information has been filled for me.
So, right now, you should have the future app in the company portal I want to say yes.
And then you can just check if the information you hear is like, all right, what does
something for me?
You don't want to.
You cannot actually modify it like the package added identifier.
So, right now, you can see the publisher is going to be Microsoft Corporation and then you
can feel some more like information here yourself.
So, I'm just going to click Next for that.
And then for the assignment, I says available for on-road device, I'm going to just say add
all users for now what for we can't only just select the specific group, but let me just
click add all users and then click Next.
And then we can tell every few what we just created and then I can just click Create.
So, by clicking Create, you can see that the app now has been created.
So, right now, the app has been created, it's going to be deployed to all the devices
in our environment.
So, what I can now do is put up the deployment is I want to go to the device, I only have
some few devices here that have the sync to consume from my own premises.
So, let me say, I have this Windows 10, let me just sync, let me do sync, let me go
and say yes, I'm going to do that for all devices and then we cannot check if it has been deployed
to the devices.
So, I'm just going to sync with this as well.
So, I'm just syncing my device phase and then if I go now to my Windows 10 device, here
we can see we just have the maximum remote desktop tool, desktop that has been deployed
to this device and we cannot decide that to I truly install it on this device, here you
can see we cannot set to install, if I go to the 3D, I can't really share it as well.
But, let me just click Install to start the installation process on this device and then
if I go to my Windows 11, here sometimes it may take some time for this app to be downloaded
to all your devices, but what you can't really do, we can't just set to see if we have
any download, if you see that it's taking some time to download, you cannot go to settings,
from one settings, we can now actually sync this device with Intune, so you can't really
do the same for your other devices, for example, we can say we have some app that has been
deployed to this device, which I knew, well if you're not seeing still not app, we can
decide to go to Settings, and on that settings we cannot click Sync, and mind you the sync
can't take some time, or at some time you can see that the app has just been deployed
to your device, so if we go back again to the device where the app is being downloaded,
you can see the app is still downloaded, you can see that there is a Microsoft remote desktop
tool, it's been downloaded right now, and after short time it will be installed.